MAKSIM POSTNIKOV

Coquitlam, BC | max@postnikov.dev | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Frontend developer with 5+ years of experience in designing and building integration-ready, user-friendly web applications using a wide-range stack of technologies such as React, TypeScript, TailWind, Bootstrap and other modern tools and frameworks. Proficient in building software from scratch and working with legacy code. Innovation-driven problem solver with the focus on user experience improvement and customer engagement.

KEY COMPETENCES

- Responsive Web Design & Mobile First approach
- WCAG & ADA web accessibility compliance
- Cross-browser compatibility
- Version control / Git
- Web apps performance & durability optimization
- Testing automation and code debugging
- Backend foundational principles
- Agile / Scrum methodology
- Work independently or as a part of the team
- CI/CD practices

TOOLS

Development Stack: HTML/CSS, JS, TypeScript, React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, REST API, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Gulp, Twig, Webpack, GIT, Docker, BEM, SPA, AWS services, CraftCMS, JEST, PWA, ES6, ESLint, AWS.

Methodologies: Agile (Scrum), Waterfall, Kanban.

PM Tools: CRM, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Notion, Slack, G-suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

WiseUpStudio SC, USA Frontend Developer Mar 2020 – Aug 2023

Developed websites, PWA and specific interactive components, provided code review. Applied frameworks (React/Redux, Bootstrap, Tailwind) and bundlers (Gulp, Webpack) as well as used pure HTML, CSS and TS. Following best practices using BEM, Responsive Web Design and Mobile First application principles. Created MERN based backend and REST API for web apps.

- Created new websites from concept in collaboration with other developers and solo using HTML, SCSS and TypeScript based on Gulp+TWIG or Webpack+React.
- Improved sites loading speed up to 35% by optimizing images loading and reducing amount of requests when possible, created SPA to improve user experience.
- Implemented Progressive Web Applications technology increased the user satisfaction level up to 95%.
- Applied responsive design techniques so the websites could be viewed on any device as intended increased mobile traffic at 60%.
- Participated in peer code reviews as appropriate for the task at hand and using TypeScript cut amount of user error reports up to 35%.
- Updated REST APIs to reduce network traffic up to 65% and improve app performance at 25%.
- Implemented cache strategy for Express based backend to reduce amount of requests to MongoDB up to 90%.
- Used AWS to create NodeJS based backend which reduced annual maintains costs at 60%.

- Collaborated with product designers to develop new features as specific-designed galleries and carousels, theme switchers, etc.
- Boosted code efficiency by 25% by identifying and fixing bottlenecks.
- Created templates and maintained CraftCMS based websites.
- Followed accessibility best practices to meet WCAG & ADA accessibility compliance.

ServiceComIrkutsk, RussiaJunior Frontend DeveloperJan 2019 – Feb 2020

Created websites using pixel-perfect or adaptive design in collaboration with designers and senior developers. Created mocks. Participated in code reviews and worked with senior developers.

- Developed and maintained websites using HTML/CSS/JS and Bootstrap/Gulp/TWIG, created adaptive design, using BEM and ES6 to meet the high development standards.
- Developed code to convert design wireframes or mock-ups into pixel-perfect website elements under supervision.
- Participated in code reviews and worked with senior developers to improve code quality and best practices.

EcostroySystem Engineer

Jun 2015 – Jan 2019

Planned strategy of IT development, configuration of security settings and access permissions for individuals and groups, implement the complex virus malware protection strategy. Communicated with third party System Engineer Groups for create optimal solutions for business support.

- Performed in-depth analysis of system trends to identify and solve problems and to improve technical capacity to meet usage demands, supervised Technical Engineer Teams during complicated projects.
- Created new enterprise disaster recovery strategy and standards for day-to-day servers, network and data backup system operational support, Implemented new technologies optimized operational efficiency up for 30%.
- Created the specific Software for small groups, providing integration with Microsoft Office. It helped to avoid data entry mistakes and speed up operations on up to 80%.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING AND EDUCATION

Professional Scrum Master, <u>PSM-II</u>, Certificate Scrum.org, 2023

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, <u>AWS CCP</u>, Certificate AWS, 2022

Frontend Web Developer, Certificate SkillFactory Educational Platform, 2019

Major in Computer Information Systems, Master's Degree Baikal State University, Russia, 2005

SOFT SKILLS

- Flexibility and adaptability to adjust to changing project requirements and priorities.
- Creative problem-solving skills to find innovative solutions to design and technical challenges.
- Ability to work independently or as part of a team.
- Strong work ethic and a commitment to delivering high-quality work.